This is software engineering radio, the podcast for professional developers on the web at se-radio.net.
SE Radio is brought to you by the ITE computer society and by it e software magazine online at computer.org/software.
[music]
Welcome to software engineering radio. I'm your host Adi Narayan and I'm here today with Vive Yadav and we're talking about building regression test harnesses for microservices at scale.
Vive is an engineering manager at the payments company Stripe where he spent nearly a decade building payment cost estimation, billing and pricing infrastructure.
In short, systems that estimate what it costs to move money on the internet.
Vive, welcome to software engineering radio.
Thanks for having me. Is there anything about your background that I missed to mention that you'd like to add?
Uh just one more thing to add there that yes before stripe I was working on a bunch of startups and the last startup I worked on was also payments related and it still is doing pretty good. Wonderful. I'm really looking forward to this conversation.
There's a lot of interesting stuff uh that I'm looking forward to cover.
So let's get started with just the basics.
What are the different kinds of tests that engineers often write for microservices?
Yeah, so they come in a full suit of tests.
So like first one would be basically your unit tests which are really just trying to test your basic functionality a function level functionality essentially.
Then comes the functional test which go a bit broader and just are trying to test some functionality at a class level or couple of classes level and so on.
And from there on you have integration tests which
try to test across more complicated boundaries across different modules or across different services and so on.
And beyond that it is much less formalized but different companies or different teams might come up with unique novel testing strategies that suit their unique need and we will talk about one of those here today.
So in the context of microservices you run an engineering team when a team writes or migrates a microser what does that testing strategy look like?
Talk me through the process of figuring out what they should test for and how they should sort of think about the problem. Yeah.
So, especially in the context of migration, usually there's a goal of a migration, right?
So, you are generally trying to move from one system to another system.
Most of the times you want to preserve the behavior and want to extend the capabilities so that you can do new stuff with the same code while making sure that the old stuff continues working as it was working.
So, most of the migrations in the beginning are like for-like migrations that unlock a future capability.
And in a like forl like migration, you need to make sure that your past behavior is not changed.
You're able to support that kind of traffic and capabilities exactly as it was before.
It is very important to make sure that your service behavior is preserved.
Got it.
So when you mention like for like testing and migrations, this is essentially let's say if you're migrating Python for instance or if you're going from one database to another,
you want the behavior of the microser to be exactly the same, the same inputs, same outputs, uh nothing and you want to test it for all possible scenarios. Is that accurate?
Exactly.
Someone basically living outside the system may not even notice that a change happened.
That would be a gold standard.
So just to take an example, let's say you have a old payment stack.
Hypothetically speaking, let's say you have some stuff written in mainframes and you can write that in Rust today.
Your system has been running for 40 years.
It is doing critical payments and you want to make sure that all the historical stuff keeps working as it was working before while you change things under the hood.
That would be a like for like migration.
And when you're thinking about building these test suites, is it does it happen in sequence?
Do you sort of, you know, first do the unit test, then the integration test, and then eventually get to the regression test, or do they all sort of happen in parallel?
I think the code writing does h happen sequentially but
the planning should happen thinking the end goal up front because some of these test scenarios which is unit tests,
functional tests or integration tests it is easy to do them layer by layer and that works naturally but
if you want to have some more esoteric testing as we had in our case we had to think about that testing up front while designing the code base and the layout of the codebase.
case because we have to structure the code to enable that testing up front and so it depends on the scenarios.
Code writing can happen sequentially but planning should think through all things up front.
Got it. Got it.
So I think most engineers can relate to this.
You migrate a service.
It could be a like forl like situation.
uh you write through a test suit sweet everything passes and then something breaks in production that no one predicted.
From your experience what do people often miss?
From my experience the things people miss are really tail end scenarios which happen very infrequently like team does not have collective memory of them.
Those are not really recorded in your existing test suit.
It depends on like how many different scenarios your service have to work through.
But in many practical uh production scenarios,
these test cases are in millions and so you cannot really enumer en enumerate them one by one in your test files whether unit test or functional tests.
In those scenarios, we uncover some corner cases which no one could keep in memory essentially.
Understood.
Now when somebody's you know like when a new developer is learning to code they of course learn about tests and they start writing test test driven development where you're building a service or you're building a function and you're writing tests around it.
I think what you're talking about is orders of magnitude more complex and you've written two blog posts on the stripes website which walk us through these scenarios to lay the context for people.
Can you give us an sort of an idea of what the system looks like?
what are these sort of big systems that you're working on where testing especially regression testing plays a huge role.
Let's lay out the context as to what this example looks like.
Absolutely.
I'm going to take maybe 2 3 minutes to just set it up maybe a little longer but it will really help us along the way.
So as an example, let's take an example of payment costs.
So payment costs are think of them as costs of moving money on the internet.
So to give you an example, let's say that you are buying some shoes on Amazon and you are paying $150 for those shoes.
Amazon is going to get about 145 146 out of that
150 and the $23 difference is essentially going to different parties in the payment stack.
So a a most uh relatable example is you have the these different credit cards and
these credit cards will say if you use this credit card we will have um you know 3% cash back or some other rewards and so on.
All these rewards are funded by something known as interchange.
So essentially when you are doing this $150 transaction on the internet about $23 of that is going as a interchange fee to the card issuer the bank who issued you the card.
So that's one party in the payment stack.
Then there is card networks Visa, Mastercard or other card networks worldwide.
And these card networks have their own fees in different forms.
Those fees are known as scheme fees.
And so each transaction would have more than one scheme fee.
And these are fractional fees.
sometimes they're fraction of a cent as well and so on.
So there could be many parties in the payment stack which are enabling that payment to happen and they are taking their fee.
So now if you from one transaction if you scale to the internet economy so
let's say in the case of stripe stripe last year processed about $2 trillion and assuming let's say on an average worldwide there is 2% network cost that
comes out to be about $40 billion of network costs.
So we built systems at stripe which are estimating these network costs and trying to sort of make sure that
we are correctly sending right data to the network so that we are not overpaying and so on and these network costs depend on a lot of parameters.
So to give you an example just in US visa there are more than 60 parameters that impact a card a a single transactions cost and now you can scale that to different networks.
So let's say there will be Mastercard, there will be AX and others.
And you can now scale it to different countries as well.
Canada will have slightly different things, Europe will have slightly different things, APEC has different things.
So a card transactions cost is impacted by more than 100 parameters worldwide and
that forms a very fat tail of scenarios which are very hard to enumerate in normal unit test or functional test scenarios.
The best thing we have for these scenarios is we have our historical data.
So networks do report some of these cost at a transaction level back at a some delay and so based on that
historical data we are able to sort of have a good sense of what does correct cost look like and
based on that we can then form a test harness that can test the changes on our historical data.
So let's say if I change some code or configuration, we can run that on the historical data to see what would have been the impact of this.
We might have some expectation that they should not have any impact and we can detect if there are any changes and we go in the other direction as well that we expect some changes and we just want to figure out the magnitude of changes.
Got it.
I think there's a lot to unpack there.
So let me sort of summarize this for our listeners and tell me if I've got this right.
when you go to an website or we go to Amazon or any other place and buy something I pay a certain amount but then there's a lot of middlemen middle parties that are involved in this transaction and everyone takes their cut.
Naively I used to think that you know it would just be five a 1% transaction cost or something like that
but it turns out that for I think Visa alone there's 60 plus parameters that are involved in estimating all these middle parties little cuts and
it's very important to keep those synchronized keep them updated so that as a payments company you're able to estimate all of these costs instantly and
make sure that the right p right entity is getting the right amount is that correct so there are not that many entities entities the number of entities is fairly limited but
there are different fees and a single entity might have different fees.
Uh so the 60 parameters you talked about they impact which fee will apply and to what degree they will apply but the number of fees is relatively smaller per transaction.
Got it.
Can you give us an example of what these 60 or so parameters? Can you take a few examples?
What are these parameters like? Like what what is a one of those parameters?
Yeah.
So let me categorize that into three buckets.
So one bucket will be just the characteristics of the transaction itself.
So where is the transaction happening?
Is this a card present transaction or it's a online transaction?
Are you doing tap to pay or are you entering your manual card number? Right?
Did you provide your zip code or not with the card transaction?
So those are the sort of transaction related properties.
Then there are some properties which are merchant related.
Where is merchant located?
What type of merchant is this?
Is this a fuel transaction or is this a telecom transaction or is this a retail transaction?
Factors like that which are merchant dependent.
Then comes some other factors which are about how what's the level of data you are providing to the network.
So there are things called level two and level three data which is like level two data would be like are you telling the network how much of is the stacks versus not in the total amount is the tip involved or not.
Level three data will be full itemized receipt of this thing.
And so all of these parameters impact network cost.
Another big thing is is this a crossber transaction.
Is there a F effects happening during this transaction.
So there are many many of these things.
I just named probably 10 of these. Got it.
That's yeah again I used to think that you know it's a.5% service charge but clearly there's a lot more going on behind the scenes.
Thank you for that example.
Is it given that you know there are all of these things going on as I understand it some of these parameters could be yes no types is it a card present card not present but
or it could also be a whole bunch of metadata linked to that
transaction itself so it's sort of is it right to think of these parameters as metadata linked to a transaction effectively yes all of these will be metadata to a transaction and
yes some of them are yes no ultimately all of them boil down to some sort of a enum and a enum have a variety of values.
Understood?
Yeah, that's it's useful to that example sort of useful to think about this and these parameters can keep changing, right?
I'm guessing that like say if I would if I had a Chase Sapphire card versus a CH Chase Sapphire Reserve card, do the information like that would also be relevant for from the context of these interchange prices.
Yes, very relevant.
So that particular thing is known as card type.
what type of card you have and some whether it is debit or
credit or pre prepaid and within credit there is many other levels and yes all of that is very relevant got it okay so
from an engineering side and you've given an example of what this looks like in the real world in terms of the different fees and
different entities from the engineering side what does this look like what do all of these you
know parameters these billing types these card types what does it look like from under the hood yeah so I can try try to distill that to a very relatively simple form.
See, ultimately all this boils down to there is some information that is going to the network during a authorization or
a settlement call and networks are estimate actually are calculating the real network costs based on the this data and based on certain rules.
Now as long as for a given transaction all the rules are known and
the data that is being sent known then it is then it is possible to actually estimate the cost of the transaction effectively by reverse engineering the behavior.
Does that answer your question?
So let's try to sort of think about this in a different way.
When a transaction comes in when a person buys something on the internet there is the amount that they paid and then there's all of this metadata or the chain of information linked to this.
Now when it comes to a payment provider like stripe what happens under the hood owned transaction.
So again taking an example of let's say you're buying shoes on the internet.
When the first time transaction is happening there's a authorization call that is going to the network.
So network could be network will be your card holder.
So if it is a Visa card the call will go to Visa.
If it is a master card the call will go to that.
But the first call is a authorization call only and that is the only realtime call.
There is no money movement happening in that call.
So we'll call Visa.
Visa will call the issuer bank.
Issuer bank will check if this is does the user even have the funds or not to spend on this transaction and they'll say yes or
no. So ultimately in the response of authorization call all you get is a promise that the bank will pay the money whoever brings the promise to the bank. So that's step one.
Now Amazon is a good example here.
The second step of this transaction will be a authorized a sorry a settlement or a capture that happens when Amazon actually ships you the shoe.
So you bought it today maybe shipping happens 2 days later that's when Amazon will say hey bank give me the money now I have sent the merchandise to the user and that step is known as settlement.
There are two separate calls.
The first call is real time.
The second call is actually not real time. that happens as a batch file.
A lot of transactions get batched together and sent to the network together.
As a response to that batch file, the the banks and the networks will essentially move the money.
Just one more thing during that moment of money, they will take their fee out of that.
So you ask for 150, they'll say here's 146, we have taken our fee out of it.
As a payment provider, does Stripe figure out what these interchange fees are at the first stage or at the second stage?
We do at both the stages.
The first stage also costs some money, much little compared to the second stage.
We figure out all these costs all along.
So we don't wait on the network.
Now it may happen that our estimate might differ from the network and that's a accuracy metric we care about.
Understood? Okay. So this is yeah this is great.
Thank you for explaining how these things work and sort of letting us peer under the hood.
Now from a testing point of view you have all of those parameters and there's some sort of a decision-m rulesbased engine that is working on these parameters.
What do unit test cover?
What do integration tests cover and what gets missed?
Yes.
So unit tests will cover for basic functionalities.
So as an example just to really dumb it down a transaction or a specific fee might have a fixed component and a variable component.
So when I say fixed component it's like this fee means 1 cent every time this fee is charged.
A variable component will be it charges.1% every time this fee is charged and we will have some logic written to calculate these things based on certain amount on the transaction. Right?
Is that logic working correctly?
So that kind of small small logic that overall combined together chain together to form the total experience that's where sort of the unit tests come in.
Another example would be just translating the stripe API request to sort of let's say network language and that translation has a bunch of logic.
Is that logic correct or not?
So every small small pieces of logic is where unit tests come in.
But they cannot really cover for all the potential varieties in which different logic pieces can be combined to actually have a full transaction end to end.
Understood? So let me unpack that.
So for unit test it could be things like card present versus card not present.
what the parameters look like across MX, visa, whatever different kinds of entities and you can do this for different kinds of parameters for each parameter and all its possible permutations.
But when it comes to all of these 60 parameters and all the possible ways in which these things could be different and interact with each other, that's not something that any unit test is going to cover.
You need something far vaster than that. Is that correct?
Yes, exactly. Far vaster than that.
And also it is about getting confidence on changes like a stable system is good.
It will always have changes.
Can you be confident that the changes are correct and as expected and it is very hard in this domain to get that confidence just out of unit tests or functional tests for that matter.
Great and thank you for that setup.
So now tell us how does one become confident about these kind of changes.
So the regression testing problem comes from a desire to be very confident about the changes being made on a service.
So in our case we are responsible for estimating network cost for stripe.
It's a very sensitive area and the cost of error is pretty high.
So any changes we make especially the bigger changes we want to make sure that those changes have exactly the right impact that we want.
Again in at the stripe scale previous year our network cost as an estimate would have been about $40 billion.
If you really drive that sort of let's say to a normal number just to think about on a day-to-day basis if our costs are wrong by even.1%.
That can add up to $5 million in error on a daily basis.
So this is where we have to be sort of extremely careful about these systems and sort of measuring our changes correctly.
So sometimes let's say we are doing a code refactoring and we want to make sure that it has no impact on the outcomes because the number of permutations on transaction cost is so high.
We are not confident that a unit test framework will give us the right level of confidence.
And so what we built is a test harness that can run on historical data whether one month data or
one year worth of data leveraging spark to run this historical data through the core logic.
So we can run through the older logic versus newer logic, produce two different outputs and compare the outputs.
And in a code refactoring, we expect the output to be the same.
And if output is not the same, we will get a very granular transaction level diff as to where it is differing.
That difference helps us figure out the bug in our logic.
And if there's no difference, then we get the confidence that the change is safe and we can roll it out without worrying about losing money. That is great.
Yeah, thank you for explaining it that way.
For someone who's not worked with Apache Spark, what does it look like and what does it do and what does it like when you say build this logic on Spark or run this in a Spark harness? What are you talking about?
In in our case, we have a micros service which generally does normal microser stuff.
Receives a request, does some logic, send some response, does some DB rights.
We also have a need to test the same logic on historical data as I just I was talking about.
So we have arranged our service in a way that IO layers are completely separate from the core logic.
So our core logic behaves just like a library that receives a function call effectively and gives a response and this is built on top of Java.
So we are able to wrap that same code library with a spark wrapper as well.
Now spark wrapper when
I say that let me just set up spark for
a second spark is a offline processing data processing engine effectively spark scales linearly it can read
from cold storage so think sort of s3 and disks and so on and it is massively parallel so
the way it works is it does bulk reads and bulk writes and the compute happens on different nodes so
data travels to these nodes nodes and travels back.
But all this read reads and writes are happening on normal files.
They're not happening in a DB setup.
So they are much much faster and it is way easier to spin up and scale down a Spark cluster compared to spinning up a sort of a or a MySQL cluster.
Now in our case we have historical records of our request responses available in S3 and
that enables us to
run sort of a spark job on them read them invoke the the cost estimation on this library I
was talking about and record the response and once we have that we can then do further analysis.
That's great.
So am I right in thinking about this as you have historical data.
So effectively cold storage of transactions all of those 60 parameters for each transaction and the outcome of the transaction which
is what the cost was for the interchange cost was going back say you know 2020 and even earlier and all of that is stored in some way in some S3 data set and
Spark is able to for each transaction each time you
change something it could be a change in the code for some small microser part it could pull up those five years of data run the same transactions again and see if the output is the same or not and do this really fast. Is that accurate?
Absolutely. Yes.
So we use the word cold storage and I think not everyone may have the same idea of what it that means in the context of a payment company.
What is cold storage?
And I take it that's a pretty big project by itself.
So what does your cold storage look like?
I would say companies of stripe scale and even bigger companies u they do have a bunch of data analysis needs and
data analysis needs are kind of different from your realtime transaction processing needs.
So most of the companies I know about do have a bunch of their sort of request response logs or some other data available in cold storage.
It's just a normal hygiene stuff you do as you scale up.
There are very standard like ETL shaped.
So ETL is export transform and load I think type shaped work that
happens which for any sort of key historical data sometimes you know because of regulation as well that these companies store.
I do want to call out one thing there.
Stripe and companies in similar domain are extremely careful about what is stored in these cold stoages.
So none of the sort of personally identifiable information and things of that shape are never stored.
In these cases we are just storing transactional data, transactional properties, they don't identify a person.
They just identify type of a transaction effectively.
Got it?
So if I go back to the example of buying something on Amazon, it won't include the fact that who I was, what my age was, or even what the shoe was, but it's more of this is what the transaction looked like,
this is where it was made, and the card parameters perhaps, and then the outcome. Correct?
Yes. Yes. Got it.
You said a few other things a little while ago that I think we should think and unpack.
First you run this whole suite of tests, suite of regression tests on a spark cluster and then it it runs the whole thing and it tells you hey look it's either the same or it's different.
Uh what scale are we talking about? Like is it tens of tests?
Is it hundreds of tests?
What what does this kind of to get the conf to go back to the idea of I feel confident that this change is okay?
How many tests should be done in this scenario?
What we are really doing is we're not running a test.
We are essentially running all a bunch of historical data through the new set of things.
So let's say you had old code and you have new co code, right?
So you're trying to run old transactions through new code.
So to give you a sense of scale, hypothetically speaking, let's say stripe has 100 million transactions a day.
Each of these transactions will have correspondingly about 500 million different cost items on a daily basis.
And so if I say one year worth of data, we are talking about I don't know north of 30 billion transaction input and out about 5x of that on the output side.
If you talk about a week, it'll be much smaller.
So we are running all these transactions through the spark system essentially and getting a response back and then comparing the output with the historical data.
So it's less about number of tests.
It's more about number of transactions we run through.
And how do you decide that like is it this is a small change I should run it on one day's worth of transactions or this is a big change I should run it on a week's worth of transactions.
This is I would say just the SOPs of the system depending on the sensitivity and depending on the use case.
So change is one type of use case.
The other type of use cases actually we should talk about where it is useful but it really depends on the need.
So most of the scenarios we essentially run a week worth of transactions and if there's no change great if there's some change run for a longer time get more data and then help in debugging.
Understood.
Okay, let's dig into what a the design of a regression test system looks like. Let's try this out.
Like if you were to draw this as a diagram, what would be the different components uh for a system of this type?
So you have the cold storage which has all of the information, all of the transaction records going back x number of years.
You have the microservices living in some place and then each time a change is made, this job takes over and it runs it through a week's worth of transactions.
When that is finished, do you get a report?
Do you get just the delta of the things that failed and who gets the report?
Is it the person who's built the test? Is it someone else?
Is it sort of a team that gets it?
What do you do with that sort of a result?
So, let me set that up and then I'll talk about a bunch of scenarios around that.
So, first of all, by definition, this is about regression testing.
So, we have to have some historical data against which regression is being done essentially.
So the first requirement for this thing to work is like hey yes your request responses historical request responses are available to read and compare.
That's one.
The second thing is your overall code base should be arranged in a way that
it is working in sort of real-time service environment as well as it is wrapped in a spark wrapper and the wrapper is ready all the time.
So essentially if you're making core code change that changes the core logic the logic essentially gets wrapped as a library and then library is a dependency of essentially a spark wrapper.
So they essentially change together by definition that's just part of your build system. So that's one part.
Now let's say that I make a code change right now and I raise a PR.
When I raise a PR, I can comment on that PR with a specific tag.
And by doing that specific tag, I am essentially telling a system that we have preset up to invoke specific Spark job with a input of one week worth of data.
So that one week worth of data is pre-identified.
It gets refreshed every week, but that's identified on a location.
And so with that input, we invoke the Spark job.
The Spark job runs through Airflow in a cluster.
And when it is done, there's second spark job that will run which compares again the corresponding one week output with the new output and it has a predefined format.
So it basically prepares a report.
The report anyone can read that report who has access to it but it attaches that to the PR and so with that the PR reviewer and the writer both have the access to the output.
So that's one way to invoke it when I'm making code changes.
There is another way which is these networks keep time to time changing the rules of how these fees are to be calculated.
So that kind of thing happens every quarter and every 6 months there are relatively bigger changes and so on.
So in this whole system either code could change or the configuration could change.
The rules are the configuration and so we could run so when configurations change especially when
networks changed we'll try to run about year worth of transactions to estimate the impact of those changes and in that
case there's a separate sort of the same spark job is basically prepackaged to run on a year worth of data with sort of a new input which are the new rules and
it will run that and produce a report in that report changes are expected and we are trying to understand the changes in the impact of those changes.
Got it. A lot of stuff there.
Let me try to summarize a couple of things.
One thing that you mentioned was know I think something around the code is working on a real time level and as a spark wrapperable object.
What I meant took that to mean is you write something you build a tool which should work right now for whatever transaction processing but
it should also be wrappable within the subspark job in order to do this historical analysis.
And in order to do that, it needs to conform to certain standard design patterns. Correct?
Yes. And those design patterns that you mentioned earlier where you know classic ones separate the core logic from the side effects like you know if you're do if you're doing a calculation just do the calculation don't mix it with writing to a database and so forth.
Is that what you were thinking about?
That's most of it really.
Got it.
when you run these huge jobs and I think the the distinction that you made was very good which was you know you could either change the code that stripe has to process it or
you could change the characteristics of the parameters configurations each of those things could change sometimes both could change but
you want to be able to isolate one thing and test do the regression test for that and then isolate the other thing is that
a good way to think about it yes correct got it I get the part where you're changing the code so say I migrating I'm doing a standard there is some particular data database that
the company uses we're switching to something else we are migrating all of those things my internal code changes so
then I run this whole flow of transactions again with the new code when it comes to configurations what am I running again is it because
the transaction is no longer the same right the configuration itself means transaction is different do you you see what I'm trying to say like what gets tested again what gets run again yeah so
configuration changes are essentially the rules that determine the network cost.
So effectively what's happening is a transaction has a proper its properties.
So those are not the changes I'm talking about.
I'm talking about the network rules.
So for example, networks will say if you pass AV on a transaction then we will not charge you like a a specific fee.
It's known as AVS fee.
But if you don't pass it then I will charge you a fees.
Okay.
It says am I right in like if I if I sort of simplify this this could be oversimplifying like there is the metadata for a transaction and
there is the interpretation of the metadata the metadata might mean something it might not mean something and those things are what can change like certain things which
before didn't cost anything suddenly could cost something exactly so the rules of the game might change the transaction properties are the same but
the rules might change and if the rules change what are you comparing it to though because say I bought the same shoe in 2024 uh the interchange fee something some minor thing was 01%.
Right? Now it's become 05. The output is going to be different, right?
So what are you comparing exactly?
Yes, that's a very good question.
So let's look at the second side of this equation now.
So stripe is a platform.
A lot of merchants are processing on this platform and stripe does have a product which is interchange plus billing.
That basically means that all the big companies are saying, "Hey Stripe, why don't you pass the co cost of processing directly to me and charge some markup on top of that?"
That is the predominant way of billing payments essentially.
Think of it as like cost plus way of billing.
So when networks change the rules, stripe gets impacted.
Yes, but also our users get impacted.
So again, let's say that you are Amazon and Amazon is processing on Stripe.
Amazon wants to figure out so networks will say you know starting on April 1st the rules that determine network cost are changing and
now Amazon needs to figure out what will be my impact of this.
Now, Stripe could run Amazon's transaction.
Stripe could encode the new rules in our system and run historical Amazon transactions through the new rules and
then produce the output and compare that with the old fact and produce a diff and can give a guidance to Amazon.
Then hey Amazon based on our understanding the new rules are likely going to decrease your cost in these these areas and increase your cost in these these areas.
And so Strive will produce a guidance for our platforms and that guidance then helps them determine how to sort of figure out their unit economics.
That is so yeah that is that is very interesting cuz it's almost like you know when
you think about you know any software company any uh engineering organization you're thinking about testing and unit testing and all of that to make your code better catch bugs things like that.
It's sort of an internal use case.
What you're saying is the regression test. Yes, it's an internal use case.
We don't want to make mistakes and lose money.
But the same regression test is also quite a strong benefit.
It it provides value to a customer as well.
For a big customer like Amazon, they can use that regression test output, I guess, packaged in a certain way to say,
hey, this new card that Visa has launched will be, you know, x% cheaper or more x% more under certain circumstances.
So that and that kind of data is useful.
It's a useful business input that they can use for decision-m. Exactly. Yes.
That's fascinating. I never thought about that.
I was like, it's a great way to sort of think about it in terms of what value regression testing can offer from you know this whole system that you have right now. Uh there are many parts to it. There's the cold storage.
There's the ability to spark that's able to spin up take the code that you have microservices wrap it and run it you know for a week's worth of data and even more.
What was the hardest part to build it?
The hardest part was to start the overall code base with this mindset that we are going to adhere to these principles and
arrange the whole code in a way that it is aminable to the same core is aminable to both realtime path as well as a spark batch path.
Uh that took us we tried bunch of other things that was not the first obvious decision.
We wanted the regression testing but we were not sure spark would be the right thing or not.
But ultimately yeah once we landed on that it took few months to organize the initial code base but after that has been fairly easy.
Why was that difficult because it at some level it seems logical right?
Separate the core logic from side effects and things like that.
The design patterns seem fairly standard. What was the hard part there?
I don't think anyone had done a spark based regression thing.
So it's I'm simplifying it a little bit but ultimately any service when it starts it needs to load some context and the usual pattern on services is that
load the context from DB and so even small things let's say FX rates which
is relatively small configuration effectively are like yeah you read from DB when
you need them but you have to still arrange your sort of for a single request arrange the process processing in a way that
all the reads that will be needed later in the pipeline gets done up front and a context is prepared for that transaction and then that context is given to the library to execute.
Just reorienting the whole thing from that perspective was a bit of a mind sort of mindset change.
So don't load the dependencies for each transaction but load them in mass at the beginning for a bunch of transactions.
No. So that one is needed for spark.
But like even for a transaction you may load things incrementally.
Oh now I need fx rates let me load this.
Okay now I need that set of rules let me load them and now I need that. Right?
You could might do sort of the whole thing in peacemail basis.
Another way to do this thing will be load all the things up front prepare a context packet and then give it to the library to execute.
Got it. Got it. Okay. A context pack.
And as someone who's worked on migrations and I think a lot of our listeners would have worked on some migration to the other, they're already very stressful.
There's a lot of you know timelines that engineers are trying to protect and get the migration done.
How did you make the case for building a harness during a migration rather than sort of treating it as a separate project after the fact?
Yes.
In fact, because we were doing a migration, this was the easy part.
As I said, it's a very sensitive area.
We are directly dealing with money.
So migration had to be really really confident that
the new changes or the new set of new set of code is the right thing and how do we prove that the only way to prove that
like to ourselves as well was to make sure that we run the historical data on it and
as if it comes out to be the same it's great now one way people do this is they will run a new system and
the old system in parallel for I don't know depending on the use case sometimes many months And that way they generate the confidence and slowly roll out and running.
We wanted to shorten that timeline.
Basically rather than doing a month's worth of rollout,
we wanted to have confidence up front and also we didn't want to do this incrementally because
if you are doing this shadow rollout situation, you're just dependent on new transactions coming and so on.
So you you don't get too many iterations on it.
But with a spark based wrapper, we could run sort of a month worth of transaction, a year worth of transactions multiple times a week.
Like every developer could have their own Spark job running separately while they're testing different phases of it.
So it was actually a speed bump for us in terms of once the initial setup is done in terms of testing.
And so once we lay out that story, it becomes very easy to buy in for everyone.
You mean a speed boost, right? Not a speed bump. Yeah, speed boost. Sorry.
Got it. Got it.
So, essentially I think one of the things also you mentioned was you might say that the feature is being developed on a at a slow time in the markets.
I think towards the end of the year after Christmas, but if you want to really test it, you want to test it during a busy you know shopping season for instance. So, and you can do that.
You can sort of pick you can by using a representative week you can get a lot of data which you may not get if you were just sort of let it be let it sort of run in parallel or something.
Absolutely. Got it.
A couple of sort of quick questions.
You're running a week's worth of data to Spark.
That looks that sounds like a lot of compute and that can cost a lot.
And given that you mentioned, you know, developers can use it.
Like if I was built having a PR and I submit a PR and I put appropriate comment, it'll go and trigger a week's worth of Spark testing.
Do those costs add up?
Is is Spark I mean compute on Spark?
Are we talking about very large amounts uh to do these kinds of tests?
So I think we should think about two types of costs here.
So one is yes the compute cost another cost is the storage cost and then the time cost.
So once we establish that this kind of testing is needed for our needs then the only two options are either you do it with a DB or you do with spark.
Now with spark the storage is actually dead cheap compared to DB and the time cost is also way lower.
So the only cost that increases the compute cost which is not that high especially if you're doing one week 1 month worth of uh thing at a time spark costs increase a lot if
you're doing same amount of compute every day.
So let's say if you're doing multi-year worth of compute every day that's actually pretty costly but otherwise not.
So if you're testing a whole year's worth of data every day, then it's a lot.
But if you're only doing like a small amount, like say a week or something each time you release a new feature or make a bug fix, then it's not much. Correct.
Yes. Exactly. Got it. Got it.
Let's dig into a few things that you mentioned that I found interesting.
No, realtime microservices, you're querying live data, right?
Like you're hitting up databases, you're looking at feature flags, you're looking at configuration tables and all of that in order to make a decision.
How do you handle take all of these dependencies and store it in your cold storage?
Like do you because these are real-time dependencies that you're pulling from somewhere like is it all rows in a table? How does that look like?
Like how do you take take all those and put them in someplace that can then be pulled out in the right in the right sort of format for running the hardness while running the harness?
Yeah.
So that's a real consideration and that's why this whole thing I'm describing may not fit for a different use case.
In our use case the biggest thing is the transactional data that's the highest sort of let's say number of records but
other things which is let's say what determines cost of a transaction like that
kind of configuration is few thousand rules effectively worldwide so that's not that much uh and
similarly the other things like FX cost or some flags context all of those things are way lower in sort of num different number of rules So
the way we do this is think of converting every lookup you do during a real-time call into a join in Spark.
And so we do all those joins up front.
And so let's say we'll read transactions on the Spark side.
And okay, this transaction contains Australian currency and USD.
Okay, let's just load FX rates and the pick the FX rates corresponding to that.
So join on that.
So that's just one example, but there could be other joins based on that context.
But we load all of that up front, do the joins up front and then we have a context prepared and then we send it to the library.
So it comes at a additive cost.
Every time sort of we have to add a new dependency in this chain, we have to update the spark join path as well.
But those things happen relatively infrequently.
Correct me if I'm wrong.
when you say take the example of you know if
if a transaction required like you said the Australian FX would the cold storage capture the exchange rate at the time of transaction and
then save it somewhere or is it a case of you know I have the time stamp and I can go go look up the Australian exchange time series and then pull that number and connect it at the time of running the job.
Yeah, we will have it pre-tored.
Okay.
It was a snapshot at the time or everything that's relevant to the transaction at the time is stored into the cold storage.
Yes. Yes. Got it.
And since the cold storage is just a standard S3 bucket, it will be several maybe hundreds of thousands of terabytes, but it's still cheap. It's just an S3 bucket.
Very cheap. Yes. Understood. Okay.
So now I think a lot of you what you spoke about is relevant for migrations.
Outside of migrations, where else has this regression test system proved its value?
Yeah.
So I say migrations is where it pays off immediately and it's where we that's the best place to build this system but
after migrations like a few things one is code changes continuously keep happening and so migration help the system put in place but
once the system is in place you can keep using the system for any code change to detect if the code change is having the relevant impact or not.
Sometimes you expect no impact, sometimes you expect some impact and so you can detect that.
So that's one example.
The another example as I gave was sometimes networks will change the rules.
So let me try to actually give a more fashionable example.
So let's say that you are working with one of these AI companies and you have some token costs and you want to figure out and
let's assume that you had your historical request responses stored and you want to figure out what would be my cost if I changed my model from A to B and
if you could replay your data not exact data not exact sort of inference but like you know whatever matters for billing you could just figure out if
I change from model A to model B my cost will reduce by 10x X it's the same thing.
So you can use these systems to basically figure out if the rules of the system changed in my case if the network cost rules changed what would be the impact of those changes on my bottom line on my customer's bottom line.
So that's two.
The third example is sometimes incidents will happen.
Sometimes you will write wrong code or wrong configuration and estimate wrong things.
maybe send wrong cost to your customers as well and then later when you detect the incident you need to figure out what was the impact of that mistake.
The way to do that is you correct the mistake and you compare the new data with the old wrong data and you get a difference and you can attribute the difference to every transaction and
based on that figure out you know impact on every customer.
These are just few cases there a couple more that we can go into if you're interested.
All right. So one of the examples that you mentioned like you know like the token example which sort of leads into another question that I had which is outside of payments outside of a company like stripe who else would benefit from a system like this because it is a lot of investment to build it.
So I think this system really works if your area or your service is not dependent on too many dependencies. That's a requirement.
If you have too many dependencies I don't think it makes sense.
Then if you don't have that many dependencies, I think anyone who is doing a migration should just set this up.
It requires little upfront investment and pays up within the migration time frame and then keeps giving dividends especially in sort of current age where
sort of let's say cost of making changes to the code is reducing.
The cost of knowing whether the change is safe or not has not reduced.
Everyone will need some scalable systems that can actually very reliably tell you if your change is safe or not and help you the output actually helps you debug as well.
You mentioned like they should set it up and it's not that much work to set up.
What would it entail? Like so first I'm guessing you need to have a cold storage.
So which means everything that's coming in and going out put it somewhere.
Even if you can't model it too well just keep it somewhere.
Second is creating right designing your microservices in a way that they can be wrapped with in a spark wrapper right for somebody who
for folks who've never done it how hard is it to sort of shift into that role to doing that
it's a learning curve it's equivalent of saying let's say someone has not done unit tests before how hard is it to set up for unit tests it's equivalent amount of effort does it help so
it's sort of a mindset shift effectively it's a big mindset shift yes and But but it pays it forces a discipline on you that really pays up.
Understood. Understood. Okay.
In real world systems, what you're saying makes a lot of sense.
When you have everything stored and for in order to run an old transaction, you pull up that transaction, you get all the parameters linked to it and then you run it and boom, you see the output.
What if some dependencies are missing?
What if the cold storage has gaps that you didn't know they exist, but then like does the test just fail and sort of skip it?
skip and like does is that transaction ignored? What happens in situations like that?
Yeah, it depends on how critical was the dependency.
So if the dependency was absolutely critical for the functionality to happen.
So let's say in cases of for an exchange situations in in our case actually the things will fail and we'll get a error output and so that's a thing to look at.
But if the dependency was not super critical then it might fail in a way that that you don't notice up front and it might show up as a difference if there's a gap in the cold storage.
What happened? They said if it's a important if it's important then if it fails then make noise.
If not let it go is was my understanding.
Yeah.
So I think the upfront advice I will have is you should set up in a way that there's no gap in the cold storage.
You should treat the cold storage as a first class citizen to make this successful.
But if you have not done that work, then either your sort of uh work will fail or it will produce some difference.
So let's say your real-time service had some data but your cold storage did not have that data.
The impact of that will be visible in your test situation versus your uh past golden data set.
there will be a difference and you'll debug that difference and you'll realize it is coming because there was a gap in the cold storage. Got it.
And if you're in a big company like you know like in most big companies you are getting data from some other part of the company and in order to make these decisions with the microser you're pulling from different sources.
What I'm hearing you say is when if you are building a micro regression harness for your neck of the woods, whatever data you pull from other sources, even if they internal sources, you capture a snapshot and you keep it with you.
So you don't go and query those other sources at testing time.
Yes, correct.
So that is the cardinal rule of doing Spark jobs basically that you don't want to query when the Spark job is running.
You want to load all the data up front and then use joins.
Load the data up front and use joins.
Got it. Okay, understood.
Let us look at Oh, we have to get to the AI part which is you know on everybody's mind.
Given that code is so much cheaper to produce, features are faster to ship.
Does that mean that having such a regression harness increases the confidence that each new feature that's implemented could be vioded?
Even like even if it's VI coded the level of testing and sign off required before it's shipped is still high.
Yes, exactly.
So think of this as your own local eval on your service and your AI agents could be making all the code changes. As long as they pass this eval, the changes are safe. You get the confidence immediately.
Got it.
So if it's regardless of whether it's a small change or a big change, you're able to run it through a week's worth of heavy transaction data.
And if it if it if there are no diffs or if the diffs are all minor ones, you know that it's mostly safe.
Exactly. Yes. You get that confidence with this. Yes.
Got it. Got it. Understood.
One other thing that I had as someone who has run a regression tests and you know I would a CI would run and it would say hey something's failed.
It can be quite a frustrating experience because something failed. You got an error log.
you don't know if the mistake was in your code or if it is some sort of a dependency in a library that got missed or if it's something upstream that happened.
Does the testing harness make that triage process less painful or because cuz from what you said it's running so many times.
How do you make that less painful for developers?
Yeah.
So this whole thing really helps in that because most of the times output is not a error message.
The output is a different difference log.
So it will say for transaction X uh I expected output output to be $2 but it was 2.1.
So you essentially get a transaction comma fee level difference or
in in our case it was transaction comma fee level but
in any case the way this whole thing works is you get a difference at a at a very very granular level and
that really helps you pinpoint okay what is common about the the this set of um granular transactions.
Oh, all of these are UK to US transactions.
So there must be something off in that area of the code or the rules.
So you you get a lot of debug hints up front with this.
So effectively you're able to replay that particular scenario again or you'll know what those scenarios what the uh parameters impacting that scenario are.
So you can pretty much quickly go to the issue. Okay, understood.
Yes.
Does AI help with summarizing and you know making that clearer to interpret?
I have not tried that but that's a very good suggestion and I'll pass that on to the team.
Yeah cuz I'm guessing people already you must already be using it.
You may [laughter] not be aware cuz when you see these logs when we see logs coming in you're like you know what tell me what the error is.
I can you know it's especially the standard ones it's easy to use it for that. Okay.
Yeah.
Once you say it, I feel like yeah, why haven't I have thought of this before enough? Cool.
I think we've covered quite a lot of ground.
Uh, anything that you'd like to add that I may have missed out or you want to rephrase something?
Yeah, just one sort of high level thing I want to call out is like the cold storage part feels fairly sort of let's say risky.
uh and they're like we take absolute care of making sure that no privacy related or PII related data gets stored to the cold storage.
So it's that work is sort of taken care of at a very very uh fundamental infra level at stripe.
So PII meaning personally identifiable information. Correct.
Absolutely. Yes. Got it.
So none of that is and I take it there sort of standard processes around how do you scrub the data before you put it into a gold storage.
Yes. Exactly. That covers most of what we spoke about.
If people want to know more about what you do or learn about the systems you built at Stripe, where should they go look for it?
Stripe blog is one place where I have published about this one but other than that my email is vivestripe.com so they can reach out to me. Understood.
Cool.
Uh this was a really interesting conversation as you know I think a lot of us could benefit from uh regression testing harnesses getting the managements and you know engineering management to approve it to build these kind of systems.
It requires a lot of foresight and to think about all the possible ways in which they will pay off and
the example that you pointed out about using a regression test harness to even explain to a customer like Amazon how a card change transaction would impact their bottom line is really clutch.
I mean it's sort of something that I didn't think about but it can it shows the value of having such a system not just for internal use cases but also for external use cases.
So yeah thank you for taking the time and thank you for you know explaining all of these concepts in a pretty easy and lucid manner for software engineering radio.
I'm Adi Narayan for you know related episodes and a link to Vive's blog please do check out the show notes on se-radio.net and do check out our other episodes with similar topics.
Uh thank you very much and thank you Vick for sticking the time with us.
Thank you Adi.
[music] Thanks for listening to SE radio an educational program brought to you by E software magazine.
For more [music] about the podcast including other episodes visit our website at se-radio.net.
[music] To provide feedback you can comment on each episode on the website or reach us on LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter or through our Slack channel at seradio.slack.com.
[music]
You can also email us at teamseradio.net.
This and all other episodes of SE Radio is licensed under Creative Common License 2.5.
[music] Thanks for listening.